NICANOR KORIR

Software Engineer(Cloud Solutions Architect certified)

@ nicanorkorir008@gmail.com ℰ nicanor.me ♥ Nairobi, Kenya

SUMMARY

Product-orientated Software Engineer with more than 3+ years of deep technical and commercial experience developing, implementing and supporting complex software products. Acted as a Technical team lead for development of a data driven customisable Chatbot solution at SovTech and their client, Futr.ai, generated 50% growth in revenue.

EXPERIENCE

JavaScript Developer (FullStack)

SovTech 02/2021 - Ongoing Remote

SovTech is an award-winning, end-to-end custom software development company that designs, builds, deploys and maintains mobile and web applications.

- Am working with an agile, diverse and remote teams across Africa and UK to develop SAAS products using TypeScript, React JS and AWS and other technologies
- Developed a W3C compliant solution and accessible via Internet Explorer browser that lead to retaining client customer base on the new solution release
- Mentoring and supporting junior developers

Software Engineer Consultant

Incentro 08/2020 - 02/2022 Remote

Incentro is a Google Cloud Partner that helps organizations accelerate their businesses by building awesome digital solutions.

- Worked with designers, cloud architects, developers and program managers to develop, maintain and integrate web solutions with CMS tools, API third party, Google Cloud solutions and payment services
- · As a frontend lead, I worked closely with the product manager and back-end lead to launch the application within the span of 4 months
- Designed and developed reusable software components which were used in 3 different project hence reducing development effort by 50%

System Analyst & Developer

KenSwitch Ltd 01/2020 - 06/2020 Nairobi, Kenya Kenswitch is the Payments Service Provider (PSP) that facilitate commercial banks and other financial services in Kenya.

 I maintained the existing company system by upgrading development tools the latest version finding bugs and improving the system. I improved one of the Kenswitch system performance by 12%

Software Engineer

Andela 12/2018 - 10/2019 Nairobi, Kenya

Andela solves problems through technology by connecting software engineers with their clients.

- Excelled in management delivery of assigned tasks earning the highest customer satisfaction rating on software development
- Developed an interactive SVG maps solutions using d3.js that helped to manipulate geo-mapping applications and helped in faster delivering of development work

Junior Applications Developer

ICT Authority 04/2018 - 12/2018 Nairobi, Kenya

ICT Authority is a Kenyan Government Corporation tasked with rationalising and streamlining the management of all the ICT functions

 Assisted in development and maintenance of software applications by working closely with the senior developers.

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science

Kisii University

08/2013 - 03/2017 Kisii, Kenya

CERTIFICATION(S)

Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect Google Cloud

SKILLS

Client Side(Frontend)

JavaScript • TypeScript • React JS •

React Native • Vue JS • D3 JS • HTML5 •

CSS3 • GraphQL • Next JS • Gatsby JS •

UI Components e.g. Chakra •

Server Side(Backend)

Node JS • Express JS • Python • Django • GraphQL • Rest API

Database(s)

SQL • Postgres • MySQL • NoSQL • Mongo DB • Redis

Others

GIT • Figma • Google Cloud • AWS • Github • Bitbucket • Jira • Slack • Docker • Kubernetes • Angular • Babel • Webpack